Okay so, let's say we have a regular neural network which
好了 假设我们有一个普通神经网络
recognizes images and we fitted this image.
能够识别图像 我们输入了这张图
And the neural neural network guesses that the image is most likely
于是神经网络猜测这张图最可能是
a dog with a small chance of being a wolf and an even smaller chance of being a goldfish.
一只狗 小概率是一头狼 更小的概率是一条金鱼
But, what if this image is actually a wolf?
但如果这张图真是一头狼呢？
How would the neural network know?
神经网络要怎么知道？
So, let's say we're watching a TV show about nature and the previous image
假设我们正在看一个关于自然的电视节目
before the wolf was a bear and the previous one was a fox.
在狼之前的图像是一头熊 再之前是一只狐狸
So, in this case, we want to use this information to hint
这种情况下 我们想用这个信息来提示
to us that the last image is a wolf and not a dog.
最后一张图是一头狼而不是一条狗
So, what we do is analyze each image with the same copy of a neural network.
要做到这点 我们需要用同一个神经网络来分析每张图
But, we use the output of the neural network as a part of the input of the next one.
但是 我们要用神经网络的输出作为下一次输入的部分内容
And, that will actually improve our results.
这能切实提高效果
Mathematically, this is simple.
从数学的角度看 这很简单
We just combine the vectors in a linear function,
我们只需要把线性函数的向量结合起来
which will then be squished with an activation function,
代入激活函数里
which could be sigmoid or hyperbolic tan.
这个激活函数可以是 sigmoid 也可以是双曲正切函数
This way, we can use previous information and
这么做 我们就可以把之前的信息利用起来
the final neural network will know that the show is about wild animals in
最后那个神经网络就会知道节目是关于森林里的野生动物的
the forest and actually use this information to correctly
并用这个信息来正确预测
predict that the image is of a wolf and not a dog.
图像是一头狼 并非一条狗
And, this is basically how recurrent neural networks work.
这基本上就是回归神经网络的工作原理了
However, this has some drawbacks.
不过还有些问题
Let's say the bear appeared a while ago and
假设熊已经出现有一会了
the two recent images are a tree and a squirrel.
而最近出现的两张图分别是一棵树和一只松鼠
Based on those two,
根据这两者
we don't really know if the new image is a dog or a wolf.
我们无法知道新图像是一条狗还是一头狼
Since trees and squirrels are just as associated to
因为树和松鼠与森林动物的联系
domestic animals as they are with forest animals.
和与家禽的联系是一样的
So, the information about being in the forest comes all the way back from the bear.
所以 “在森林里”这个信息会一路追溯到熊的身上
But, as we've already experienced,
但我们也知道
information coming in gets repeatedly
输入信息会不断地
squished by sigmoid functions and even worse than that,
被 sigmoid 函数吸收掉 更糟的是
training a network using back propagation all the way back,
一路用反向传播往回训练网络
will lead to problems such as the vanishing gradient problem etc.
会造成梯度消失等问题
So, by this point pretty much all the bear information has been lost.
所以到这个时候 几乎所有关于熊的信息都丢失了
That's a problem with recurring neural networks;
这就是回归神经网络的问题
that the memory that is stored is normally short term memory.
其储存记忆通常都是短期记忆
RNNs, have a hard time storing long term memory and this is where
RNN 并不擅长储存长期记忆
LSTMs or long short term memory networks will come to the rescue.
于是这时候 LSTM 也就是长短期记忆网络就派上了用场
So, as a small summary, an RNN works as follows;
简单地总结下 RNN 的工作原理
memory comes in and merges with a current event
记忆输入进来 与当前事件结合在一起
and the output comes out as a prediction of what the input is.
然后输出出来 输出会预测输入是什么东西
And also, as part of the input for the next iteration of the neural network.
并作为下一轮神经网络输入的一部分
And in a similar way, an LSTM works as follows;
LSTM 的工作原理与之类似
it keeps track not just of memory but of long term memory,
它会一直跟踪记忆 不仅是记忆 而且是长期记忆
which comes in and comes out.
记忆输入进来 又输出出去
And also, short term memory,
还有短期记忆
which also comes in and comes out.
也是输入进来 输出出去
And in every stage,
每一步
the long and short term memory in the event get merged.
事件的长期和短期记忆会被合并起来
And from there, we get a new long term memory,
由此我们得到了一个新的长期记忆、
short term memory and a prediction.
短期记忆以及一个预测结果
In here, we protect old information more.
更好地保护了旧信息
If we deem it necessary,
必要的话
the network can remember things from long time ago.
这个网络可以记住很久以前的事情
So, in the next few videos, I will show you the architecture of LSTMs and how they work.
所以 在接下来的几个视频中 我会为你介绍 LSTM 的结构及工作原理